

Priyanshi Singh **Application Development Analyst**

priya.97.singh18@gmail.com

07043867185

India

Full Stack Developer with 3 years of extensive experience in C#,ASP.NET MVC and SQL experience. Expertise in Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC) of client implementations including requirements gathering, business analysis, system configuration, design, development, testing, technical documentation and support. Strong experience in providing technical documentation and status reports of the applications as per the requirement.

SKILLS

ASP.NET

SOL

ASP.NET Core, WEB API

JQuery

ReactJS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Development Associate

Nationwide Building Society(MDC)

01/2019 - 04/2020

Associate Developer

Skills Used: C#, Asp.Net MVC, Jquery, JavaScript, NUnit, WCF

Gurgaon

- Achievements/Tasks
- Designs, develops and maintains a set of enterprise class web applications in ASP.NET technologies both frontend and backend
- Working with Microsoft Entity Framework and SQL Server to maintain and enhance data Framework,
- Created technical design for the back end PL/SQL based on business requirement documents and the functional system design.
- Creation of database objects like tables, views, synonyms, materialized views, stored procedures, packages using SSMS tools like PL/SQL developer.
- Creating dynamic queries to perform ETL operations by looping through multiple database servers and tables.
- Importing and extracting data from various sources such as flat file, access, SQL server and loaded those data into SQL server to build various reports.
- Define development tasks and provides time estimates to aid in scheduling. Monitors progress against task estimates to provide
- Solely involved in all the phases of **SDLC** including Requirements Collection, Design & Analysis of the Client Specifications, Development and Deployment of the Application.
- Software development and coding, Involved in support and enhancement

Application Development Analyst

Roche Diagnostics IT(Commercial Services)

04/2020 - Present Application Developer Skills Used: C#, Asp.Net MVC, Jquery, JavaScript, NUnit, WCF, Azure, NUnit, Banglore Wix, Winodws Workflow, Sql, React Js, Rhino Mocking

- Achievements/Tasks
- Develops processes for capturing and maintaining metadata from all data warehousing components
- Lead the design and standardization of ETL processes for intake of data from both internal and external sources; Maintain data integrity via ETL coding standards and data validation
- Develop and maintain data mapping logic from the various transactional sources to the data warehouse model. Develop solid understanding of the various source data sets
- Analyzes data warehouse performance statistics and recommend improvements
- Works with peers in business and IT to define scope, project timeline, deliverables and priorities of data warehouse deliverables
- Code development of the application MSA, using C-sharp and JavaScript.
- Worked on the improvement of all programming procedures in order to make the whole software development process more effective

EDUCATION

PGD in Data Science

Symbiosis University, Pune

08/2020 - Present

Bachelor Of Engineering

Gujarat Technologial University

06/2014 - 05/2018

Ahemdabad

ORGANIZATIONS

Accenture (01/2019 - 11/2020)

Apllication Development Associate

Accenture (12/2020 - Present)

Application Development Analyst

ACHIEVEMENTS

Created a User Maintained Data(UMD) in the EDW and Datalake

Created the whole POC and tool by myself and represented it to client project got appreciation as it was the most critical User experience as expected by the client.

Won Chess Competition and TT Competitions

Multiple time Won Chess competition in Accenture in yearly competition. current score 1500 in Chess.com and also won TT completions as well. Represented School and college as well

Recognized as the emerging Resource

I was recognized as the best fresher employee in 2015 by Halliburton project

Best Organizer in Fun Friday Team

Organized fun friday events and other events with great success

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft Asp.Net MVC Web applications 70-486

Microsoft Asp. Net MVC Web applications

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals- Azure 900

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

O Tutor for new Joiners @Accenture

Accenture

Tasks/Achievements

- Taught SQL ,DBMS Concepts for New Joiners
- Evaluator Projects
- Mentor Juniors

HONOR AWARDS

Star Award Of The Month (08/2019)

Nationwide Building Society UK

Pride Award Nationwide (01/2020 - 07/2020)

Nationwide Building Society UK

INTERESTS

bibliophile

Dance

cinemaphile

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency